

FRONT END ENGINEER

Sofokleous 34, Nikaia, Athens, Greece, 18452

🛮 (+30) 6949413084 | 🗷 barka.alexandra2@gmail.com | 🔏 ale3oula.github.io | 😘 alexabarka@hotmail.com

Summary _____

I am a **Front End Engineer** with experience on building software and web applications. I enjoy creating **simple**, **clean** and **creative** user interfaces using the latest web technologies. I specialize in JavaScript and have professional experience working with Angular 2+. I also have adequate experience working with WPF (C#), Actionscript, Node.js. Currently, I am focusing on further developing my skills in Angular 7 and learning React.js.

Skills ____

Web HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.JS

Frameworks Angular 2+, Angular Material, Bootstrap, Devextreme

Programming C, C#, JAVA, ActionScript **Applications** Visual Studio Code, Intellij

Other Microsoft Office, Pages, Keynote, Adobe Suite, Figma

Experience _____

UBITECH Ltd. Athens, Greece

UX ENGINEER

Jul. 2018 - Today

• My role is to write front end components in various languages (depending the project) as well as design user interfaces.

• Technologies used: Angular 2+, JavaScript, TypeScript, Thymeleaf, AngularJS, HTML5, CSS3

Human Computer Interaction Laboratory - ICS FORTH)

Heraklion, Crete

 ${\sf Research \, Assistant \, - \, UI/UX \, Engineer}$

Jul. 2015 - Jul. 2018

- **UInify.** Developed with MEAN (Mongo.DB, Express.js, Angular 6, Node.js) stack to build a full stack application which acted as a studio for composing flexible web applications in real-time and aggregate all the individual UIs of an intelligent environment by introducing new rich user interface compositions.
- **Beantable.** Co-develop an augmented interactive table with multiple games for the Heraklion Public Library of Crete. Used C# and WPF to implement a launcher for the application and re-design various games (e.g. puzzle, classic memory games).
- Arkadi Monastery. Re-design and develop a mobile application for the Arkadi Museum in Rethimni. Used Actionscript and Adobe Flash Builder to implement a cross-platform application for both Android and iOS. [link]
- Info kiosk. Co-developed an info kiosk for the Archeological Museum of Crete, which provided information for the Minoan Culture. Developed in C# and WPF the Architecture section and some Utilities.
- Technologies used: Angular 2+, MEAN stack, WPF, C#, Actionscript, Typescript, Javacript, Node.js HTML/CSS

Education

University of Crete, Dpt. of Computer Science

Heraklion, Crete

Feb. 2016 - Nov. 2018

M.Sc. IN INFORMATION SYSTEMS AND HCI
• Grade: 9.28 / 10

- Graduate TA in CS-240 Data Structures (3 semesters)
- Graduate TA in CS364: Introduction to HCI
- Graduate TA in CS469: Modern topics in HCI
- Thesis Topic: Ulnify: A Designer Studio for creating Ul Mashups for Ambient Intelligence Environments.
- Supervisor: Stephanidis Constantine

University of Crete, Dpt. of Computer Science

Heraklion, Crete

B.Sc. in Computer Science Sep. 2011 - Jan. 2016

- Grade: 8.19 / 10
- Undergraduate TA in CS-225 Computer Organization.
- Undergraduate TA in CS-100 Introduction in Computer Science.
- Thesis Topic: Requirements analysis and development of conceptual model of an information system for food traceability
- Supervisors: Fountoulaki Irini, Plexousakis Dimitris

Publications _

womENcourage 2017 Conference

Barcelona, Spain

A Unified Interactive System for Controlling a Smart Home - Alexandra Barka, Asterios Leonidis,

Sep. 2016

MARGHERITA ANTONA, CONSTANTINE STEPHANIDIS

- Poster presentation at the ACM-W conference held in Barcelona, Spain
- ACM Scholarship to participate the conference

Volunteer _

womENcourage 2017 Heraklion, Crete

Website management Spring 2017

• Update, adding content and managing ACM - Womencourage website (Wordpress): https://womencourage.acm.org/2017/

Undergraduate Teaching Assistant

Heraklion, Crete

Winter 2015

CS 100 - Introduction to Computer Science

Answering questions on the mailing list.

· Co-assist in two tutorials.

Undergraduate Teaching Assistant

Heraklion, Crete

Spring 2015

CS 225 - COMPUTER ORGANIZATION

· Answering questions on the mailing list.

- Oral examination of two assignment.
- Marking examination scripts.

Teaching Assistance _

Graduate Teaching Assistant

Heraklion, Crete

CS 364 - Introduction to Human-Computer Interaction

Spring 2017

- · Answering questions on the mailing list.
- Examining course projects
- Marking examinations transcripts

Graduate Teaching Assistant

Heraklion, Crete

CS 469 - MODERN TOPICS IN HUMAN-COMPUTER INTERACTION

Winter 2017

- Answering questions on the mailing list.
- · Lab course for Web accessibility
- Examining course projects

Graduate Teaching Assistant

Heraklion, Crete

CS 240 - DATA STRUCTURES

• Responsible for the website and the web infrastructure of the course.

- · Answering questions on the mailing list.
- Marking examinations transcripts

Winter 2016 - Spring 2017

Graduate Teaching Assistant

CS 240 - DATA STRUCTURES

- Project co-design with another TA.
- Answering questions on the mailing list.
- Marking examinations transcripts

Languages _____

ENGLISH

2007 First Certificate in English (B2), Cambridge University

В

Heraklion, Crete

Spring 2016